要咖啡吗
Want some coffee?
来一杯吧 这可是法式滤压壶泡出来的
Say yes. It's french press.
一开始我也怀疑
I was doubtful, too,
但说实话尝过之后 普通的滤滴咖啡都是浮云
but I honestly can't see myself going back to drip.
真高兴你们终于搬离那个是非之地了
I'm so happy you don't live in a tough neighborhood anymore.
这样贸然来访 真是不好意思
We're so sorry for just dropping by like this.
你们开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me?
我巴不得和这位小公主一起呢
I'll take any chance to spend time with this little princess.
软软头发小脚丫 我打心底喜欢
I love her little hair, her little toes.
她也打从心底里喜欢她的奶奶
and she loves her grandmother.
不许叫我"奶奶"
I don't love "Grandmother."
我和小卡在修订遗嘱
So, Cam and I have been revising our will
以防天有不测风云
to specify who should take care of Lily
上帝保佑最好没有 我们想给莉莉指定个监护人
if, god forbid, something happened to us.
上帝会保佑咱俩的
God forbid.
我刚说了"上帝保佑"
I said "God for--"
所以我们多方突击
So, we've been dropping by unannounced
以对所有人选进行评估
to, you know, casually assess our candidates.
也不是"所有"啦
Not all of our candidates.
这倒是 我们没去密苏雷
No, t-that's true. We did not drop by Missour-ah.
那念"密苏里"
It's "Missouri."
真没见过自报家门还念错的
No one from Missouri would say "Missour-ah."
多有失"雷"
I'm so sorr-ah.
我们最先考虑的是克莱尔和菲尔
So, anyway, Claire and Phil were our first thought,
所以上星期突袭了他们家
so we dropped by their place last week.
恭喜您获得"史上最烂老妈奖"
You win the award for worst mother ever!
我一定会在获奖感言里感谢你
I will be sure to thank you in my speech!
菲尔 煎锅着火了
Phil, the frying pan's on fire!
我滴超人呀 大家保持冷静
Son of Jor-el! Everybody stay calm!
老爸 我想自学杂耍
Dad, I'm gonna teach myself how to juggle.
好极了 伙计
Good for you, buddy.
老妈 你们就听不见我喊救命吗
Mom! No one heard me screaming?!
我在车库里被关了大概有20分钟
I've been trapped in the garage for like 20 minutes!
而你还是没把我要的捕鼠器拿过来
And yet still you didn't get the rat traps I sent you for.
-老天 -净帮倒忙
- Oh! - Thank you.
亲爱的 锅又着火了
Honey, it's doing it again!
不是吧 每天早上都这样
Come on, now! Every morning?!
最好烧个片瓦不留
I hope the whole house burns down!
我们是不是来得不巧
Did we come at a bad time?
等上七年五个月再来吧
Come back in seven years and five months,
他们走了就清净了
when they're all gone!
煤够吗 妈妈
So, mama, you're good for coal?!
好的 好的
Okay, okay!
你可得裹厚穿暖咯
Well, you bundle up!
可别有个三长两短的
We don't want to lose you!
好的 再见
Okay. Yeah, bye!
他们正处在一场严重暴风雪正中
They're in the middle of a terrible blizzard.
难怪你要大声嚷嚷
So you shouted!
他们真的损失了两头牛吗
Did they really lose two cows?
对啊 冻得硬梆梆 妈妈会把照片寄过来
Oh, yeah, frozen solid. Mama's gonna send pictures.
好耶 又有理由去买相框了
Oh, yay, a reason to stop by the frame store.
曼尼 我带你去趟体育用品店
Manny, I got to get you down to that sporting-goods place.
-为他周末露营置点东西 -整装待发
- Got to get him some stuff for his weekend outing. - Ready!
-尿干净了吗 -待会再发
- Did you pee? Not ready.
-不介意我们跟来吧 杰 -怎么会呢
- Jay, would you mind if we came? - Sure, why not?
我想给妈妈买两双雪靴
You know, I'd like to get mama some snowshoes --
雪中送靴 鼓鼓士气
You know, to lift her spirits,
舒缓丧牛之痛
what with all the frozen cows and all.
所以牛现在就冻住了 你认为我们会相信吗
So, cows freeze now? Are we all just accepting that?
当然了 杰 就次...
Oh, yeah, absolutely. Jay, this one time --
我们分车坐
We'll take two cars.
我可以留下来照顾小公主
If you want, I can stay with the little princess.
那可太好了
Oh, that-- that's a great idea.
我去拿她的包
Oh, yeah, I'll just -- I'll just go out and get her bag.
我想带她去商场
Maybe I can take her to the mall,
给她添件新衣服
buy her a new outfit,
给她整俩发环什么的 可以吗
get her some hair rings -- is that okay?
当然可以
Yes, yes, of course.
其实呢 歌洛莉亚 我跟小卡一直商量
Um, you know, Gloria, Cam and I were talking
如果我们真出事了
about what would happen to Lily
该怎么安置莉莉
if anything were ever to happen to us,
-我们打算 -真的吗 让我来照顾她
- and we were thinking - Oh, my god. Is it? I take her!
这个嘛 你愿意固然好
Okay, well, that's very sweet,
但要明白 只有真出事了...
but you realize it would only happen --
我迫不及待啊
I can't wait!
可惜机会渺茫呀
Okay, well, hopefully, it's a long shot.
小丫头
Ay, a little girl!
一旦出事可就惨绝人寰啊
There would have to be a very tragic accident.
知道啦 知道啦
I know, I know.
你们不会出事的
Nothing is going to happen.
好吧
Oh.
万一真出了事 我可就太开心啦
But if it did, we would be so happy!
怎么样 伙计 我要开车去上班
So, what do you say, pal? I got to swing by the office.
你一起来吗
You want to come along?
去不了 我们有事要做
Can't. We got some stuff to do.
-什么事啊 -小事而已
- What? - Just errands.
我要带卢克去看儿童心理学家
I'm taking Luke to see a child psychologist.
菲尔肯定不会同意
This is something that Phil would never agree to.
他不想卢克觉得自己 异于常人
He's doesn't want luke to feel...different.
但是卢克学习不好
But Luke's grades aren't great,
而且他在学校注意力涣散
and he's having trouble concentrating in school.
我只想确保他 身心正常
I just want to make sure that he's...normal.
-妈妈快看呀 -你干什么呢
- Hey, mom, check it out. - What are you doing?
只要我晃头的速度够快
If I move my head fast enough,
这罐子看起来就像静止了一样
It looks like the can is standing still.
因为有时我怀疑
'cause sometimes I wonder.
不过我公司的女孩子
But all the girls at work love it
都喜欢我带卢克过去
when I bring luke by,
特别是那个叫海瑟的前台 是吧
especially that receptionist Heather, right, buddy?
她闻起来很香
She smells amazing.
亲爱的 恐怕你得改天再去
Mm. Well, honey, you're gonna have to
一闻你老爸前台的芳香了
smell daddy's receptionist some other time.
那香味像桃子
Like peaches.
你们都出去了 谁带我去练大提琴
If you're both going out, who's taking me to cello?
-有次 她送我一个胡迪 -亲爱的
- One time, she gave me a woody. - Sweet je--
她记得那是《玩具总动员》里我最喜欢的角色
She remembered he's my favorite character from "Toy story."
她记性好
She did.
海莉 你怎么去购物中心
Uh...Haley, how are you getting to the mall?
盖比接我过去
Uh, Gabby's picking me up.
好 那你先把你妹妹
Okay, you're gonna drop
送去上大提琴课
your sister off at her cello lesson first.
不是吧 她会打长曲棍球还会拉大提琴
No way. She plays lacrosse and takes cello lessons.
即使我那强大的坏名声 也承受不住那呆瓜的一击呀
Even my reputation can't handle that dork hit.
好吧 那你假期的时候
Okay, well, then you don't need
也不要和你的朋友去滑雪了
to go snowboarding with your friends on break.
好吧 我带她过去
Fine, I'll take her.
别跟我朋友直视
Just never look my friends in the eye,
尽量别出声
and only speak in emergencies.
-没问题 -已经犯规了
- Got it. - Ah! Already failed.
亲爱的 我去办公室露个脸
Honey, after I go by the office,
-咱们就去吃午饭吧 -不行
- maybe we can grab some lunch. - Oh, I can't.
我要把学校露营的东西都准备齐了
I got to pick up all that stuff for the school trip.
这样吧 今晚在老爸和歌洛莉亚家碰面吧
But you know what? I'll see you tonight at dad and Gloria's.
-好 -代我一闻海瑟的芳香
- Okay. - Smell Heather for me.
我一直都是充鼻 不闻
I always do...not.
邓菲夫人吗
Ms. Dunphy?
克劳斯乐医生您好
Hi, Dr. Klausner.
抱歉我们来晚了
I am so sorry we're late.
刚才路上有点堵车
We just got a little bit caught up in --
没事没事
Oh, no, it's okay. It's okay.
正好给我机会跟你丈夫聊了会
It gave me a chance to chat with your husband.
你好啊 克莱尔
Hello, Claire.
那么卢克 跟我来
So, Luke, come on in with me.
至于父母 有需要我们会通知你们的
Mom and dad, we'll let you know when we need you.
伙计 加油
Go get 'em, pal.
-你怎么 -我怎么了
- How did you -- - How did I what?
怎么知道你在这儿 除了日程表上的小记号
Know you were someplace you left no trace of
你没有留下一丝线索
except for a tiny notation in your calendar?
真挺容易的
It was quite simple, really.
我注意到日程表上的小
I noticed a tiny nota--
糟糕
Shoot.
真奇怪 我大提琴老师的车不在
That's weird. My cello teacher's car isn't here.
我真怀疑她是否在家
I wonder if she's not home.
那就敲门试试啊 艾伦·爱因斯坦
Okay, so go knock on the door, Alan Einstein.
- 不许走 还有是"阿尔伯特" -我知道
- Don't leave. And it's "Albert."- I know.
艾伦是他那个拉大提琴的呆瓜弟弟
Alan's his dorky brother who played the cello.
说得好
Good one.
我本来不应该跟你说的
I should probably not be telling you this.
-什么 -没什么 很糟的事情
- What? - Nothing. It's really bad.
快说
Tell me.
你和迪兰分手的时候
When you and Dylan were broken up,
雷切尔跟他说你是个荡妇
Rachel told him you were a skank
然后彻底偷走了他
and got all up on him.
不是吧 她对我很好的
No! But she's so nice to me.
当着你的面而已 她就会耍这种小把戏
To your face. That's how she plays.
那就让她看看咱们的小把戏
Well, now she's gonna see how we play.
我们要怎么做
What are we gonna do?
她不在家 你们把我送回家就行了
She's not there. You're just gonna have to take me home.
我们没时间 忙着呢
We don't have time. We have stuff to do.
那我就得一直跟着你了
Then I'm just gonna have to come with you.
我们不能把她放在咖啡厅
Can't we just drop her off
或者别的什么地方吗
at a coffee shop or something?
什么啊 那她要是被绑架了
What, so she gets kidnapped
我不等于惹祸上身吗
and I get in trouble?
谢谢 还是算了
No, thank you.
行 你能跟着
Okay, fine, you can come with us,
但是不管看到什么 请管好你的嘴
But you have to keep your mouth shut about anything you see.
-她会看到什么 -开车
- What's she gonna see? - Just drive!
或许我应该给我的阿姨派特也买个礼物
Ooh, maybe I should also get a gift for my aunt Pat.
我有跟你提起过她吗
Have I ever told you about her?
是一个十足的枪械狂 不留痕迹地生活着
Total gun nut, lives completely off the grid.
你看见歌洛莉亚和莉莉在一起多可爱
Did you see how cute Gloria was with Lily?
派特十分滑稽
Oh, Pat is hilarious.
我觉得她二十年都没交过税
I don't think she's paid taxes in 20 years,
但为人很热情
but very hospitable.
冰箱里总是备着一只鹿
Always has a deer in the freezer.
你有在听我说话吗
Would you listen to me?
我觉得歌洛莉亚和我老爸
I think that Gloria and my dad
可以做莉莉的监护人
could be Lily's guardians.
听着 你知道我爱杰
Look, you know I love Jay,
他们家还在名单中
and they're still in the mix,
但他养育孩子方面我还不了解
but I just don't know about him raising a child.
得了 小卡 他把我养大了
Well, Cam, he raised me.
好吧 你这话就让我陷入了尴尬的局面
Well, now you've put me in an awkward position.
看看 这真可爱
Oh, look at that. That's adorable.
看看能不能帮你找几条滑雪裤
Let's see if we can get you some snow pants.
真希望我感觉好点了
I just wish I felt better.
我觉得我有些流感症状
I think I'm coming down with flu-like symptoms.
就在去露营的前几小时吗
Couple of hours before your camping trip, huh?
我想去啊
I want to go.
只不过 要是我病了
It's just, if I'm sick,
我可能会传给监护人
I might get the chaperones sick,
要是没有监护人 就乱套了
And without chaperones, it's anarchy.
曼尼 听我说
Manny, listen to me.
伙伴制会崩溃的
The buddy system falls apart,
"后进先出"的规则就会被忽视
The principle of "Last in, first out" is ignored.
-有蝴蝶 -在哪儿
- It's butterflies. - Where?
你不过是紧张了 因为
You're just nervous because
会有很多的体育活动
there's gonna be a lot of physical activity,
而且都不是你的长处
which is not exactly your strong suit.
那地方有点让人龟缩
It is a little daunting out there.
不要对大自然用"龟缩"这个词儿
D-don't use the word "daunting" in nature, okay?
你需要一点点自信
You just need a little self-confidence.
看 他们有一堵攀岩墙
Look at this. They got one of these rock walls here.
去试一试吧
Why don't you hop up on that?
为什么
Why?
什么为什么 这可以证明你能行
Why? To prove that you can do it.
你要是能做到这个 你什么都能做到
If you can do that, you can do anything.
是吗 我能飞吗 我能讲中文吗
Really? Can I fly? Can I speak Chinese?
不 但你今晚能在我们房里睡觉
No, but you can sleep in the house tonight.
埃斯 麻烦给我孩子系上绳子 去吧
Ace? Want to wire my boy up, here? Go ahead.
抱歉我背着你来这儿
I'm sorry I went behind your back.
但是我们每次讨论卢克的问题时
But you get so defensive whenever
你总是不容分说地反对
we talk about Luke's issues.
他没有问题 是你太过担心了
He doesn't have issues. You're just a worrier.
就像你当初担心他以后不会讲话一样
Like when you thought he was never gonna talk.
他两岁那会儿 只会跟狗一样吠
He was 2, and all he could do was bark!
-我了解他 -菲尔
- I understood him. - Phil!
听着 他来看医生的事情
Look, he starts coming here,
如果被别的孩子知道 他就成了众矢之的
the other kids find out, he becomes a target,
就像跛脚的羚羊在水潭边喝水
like that limping gazelle at the watering hole
被短吻鳄发现了就会来吃它
that the alligator knows to eat.
是鳄鱼 不是短吻鳄
They're crocodiles, not alligators.
非洲没有短吻鳄
There are no alligators in Africa.
那动物园呢
How about at the zoo?
看吧 到底谁才要看心理医生
Bam! Who needs a shrink now?
-邓菲先生 邓菲太太 -什么事
- Mr. And mrs. Dunphy? - Yes?
你好
Hi.
卢克 我要跟你爸爸妈妈谈一谈好吗
Luke, I'm gonna talk to your mom and dad for a minute, okay?
好的 她简直是我见过最好的医生
Okay. She's, like, the best doctor ever.
只做了几个题 又不用打针
A couple of puzzles, no shots.
我甚至根本不需要脱裤子
I didn't even have to take my pants off.
早就应该找这种医生了
Found that one out a little late.
我以前也遇到过烂医生
I've been there, buddy.
卢克这孩子很不错
Well, luke's a terrific kid.
我是发现了一些问题 但是说实话
I have a few thoughts, but, honestly,
我觉得没有什么好紧张的
I don't see anything that's cause for alarm.
那敢情好 耽误您的时间了
Awesome. Thanks so much for your time.
我们很想听听您的意见
We -- we would love to hear your thoughts.
他是个聪明 充满好奇的孩子
Well...he's a bright and curious boy,
但是他容易分神
But he gets distracted.
我见过很多更容易分神的孩子
I see it all the time with above-average kids.
菲尔 亲爱的 给我认真听
Phil, honey, I want you to hear this.
他们会有点过度兴奋
They're a little overstimulated
因为他们对很多事情都充满好奇
because there are so many things they're interested in.
他们很难集中精力
They never seem to focus.
就这点让我抓狂
Makes me crazy.
抓狂得不得了
Too crazy.
他们长大了就不会这样了
Well, they usually do outgrow it.
-要是还这样呢 -他不会的
- What if they don't? - He will.
是有一些药物治疗方案
Well, there's -- there's medication,
但是我们得在有问题的时候才使用
but why don't we cross that bridge if we come to it?
有没有方法可以防止问题出现呢
Is there any way to avoid that bridge altogether?
或许有食疗
You know, maybe there's diet or --
或者精神集中训练之类的
or focusing exercises or something?
邓菲太太 你到底在担心什么
Mrs. Dunphy, what exactly are you worried about?
庸人自扰
Get comfortable.
我担心他会变成你这样 菲尔
I'm worried he's turning into you, Phil.
我知道我在说出这些话的时候
I knew the minute I opened my mouth
我已经错了
that I was in the wrong,
但是说实话 有时候我有点搞不懂
but, honestly, sometimes I wonder about him.
-妈 你看我 -你在干嘛
- Hey, mom, check it out. - What are you doing?
如果我头摇得够快
If I move my head fast enough,
这罐子看起来就像静止了一样
it looks like the can is standing still.
他说得太对了
He's totally right!
真有意思 你以前把你从做恶梦
I just find it interesting that you blame Jay
到膀胱害羞症这些事情都归咎于你老爹
for everything from your night terrors to your shy bladder,
现在他又成了莉莉最合适的监护人
And now he's the perfect guardian for Lily.
我没说最合适 还有
No, not perfect, and -- and
我从来没提到过我的膀胱害羞症
I never said anything about my shy bladder.
那为什么在派珀的三面元旦派对上
O-oh. Then why did I have to stand guard outside the bathroom
我得站在厕所外面放哨呢
at Pepper's three faces of new year's eve party?
给点力 曼尼 快爬 快
Damn it, Manny! Move it! Go!
好吓人啊
It's scary.
你才离地两英尺
You're 2 feet off the ground.
藤蔓爬墙都比你快
I've seen vines climb walls faster than that.
赶紧给我爬
Move your butt!
这就是曾经让你树立自信的老爸
Oh, well, there's your esteem-building parent right there.
等等 我觉得我听见未来的莉莉
Wait, wait, I think I hear future Lily
在脱衣舞钢管上面给我发来信息
sending us a message from her stripper pole --
"感谢已故的同性恋爸爸们
"Thanks, gay dead dads.
这舞是给你们跳的"
This dance is for you."
打扰一下 杰
Excuse me, Jay?
我想下来
I'm getting down.
等你爬到顶了再说 什么事
Not till you touch the top! What is it?
如果我们不这么强迫曼尼
Well, maybe if we didn't bully Manny so much,
而是演示给他看
but, rather, showed him,
他可能就不会那么害怕
he wouldn't be so afraid.
打扰一下 夏尔巴人 能帮我系上吗
Excuse me, Sherpa, can you assist me with the harness?
天啊 我的驾驶机器在哪里
Oh, no. Which one of these is my driving machine?
菲尔 我已经道歉了
Phil, I already apologized.
那是无意识 脱口而出的
It just -- it came out wrong.
真有趣 我还以为是我的问题呢
Funny, I thought that was my problem --
我出来错了
I came out wrong.
等下
Hold on.
很好 我又能走路了
Oh, good, I can walk again.
亲爱的 有时候你能表现得稍微
Honey, you know, sometimes you can act a little bit --
天啊 大家都去哪了
Oh, no! Where did everyone go?!
一眨眼就不见了
Oh, just a blink.
菲尔
Phil,
当你准备好像个成人一样跟我谈的时候
when you are ready to talk to me like an adult,
知会我一声好吗
why don't you let me know?
好的 行了 行了
Fine. Okay, okay.
成人是指那些"大"的人 对吧
The adults are the big ones, right?
你认为那是怎么挂上去的
Hey, how do you think that got up there?
我知道这看起来让人龟缩
Now, I know it seems daunting,
曼尼 但是这其实很简单
Manny, but it's very simple.
我安全地拴在绳子上
I'm securely hitched to a rope,
也就是说我不会掉下来
which means I'm not going to fall.
爸爸 你让我的日子
You know, dad, you're really making
-现在变得真不好过 -怎么说
- my life difficult right now.- How?
当我试着说服小卡
By barking at Manny like a drill sergeant
你会是莉莉很好的监护人时
when I'm trying to convince Cam
你却像教官一样地训曼尼
that you'd be a great guardian for lily.
-监护人 -没错
- Guardian? - Yeah.
你开什么玩笑
You're kidding.
杰
Jay!
算了 当我没说过
Yeah, never mind.
这真的很痛
That really hurt!
这是一个错误
This is a mistake.
为什么她要不停的说这句话
Why does she keep saying that?
因为这是她第一次听到"错误"这个词儿
Because they're the first words she ever heard.
给你 你先来
Here, you go first.
给这个荡妇一个教训
This will teach that Skank a lesson.
往她的置物柜中挤奶油
Shaving cream in her locker?
你就站在那儿把风 有人来了就叫
Just stand over there and yell if someone's coming.
她那里可能有还没
She might have homework assignments in there
交上去的作业
she hasn't handed in yet.
海莉
Haley!
-有人来了 -快跑
- Someone's coming! - Run!
-这边 这边 -好的 好的 好的
- This way, this way! - Okay, okay, okay!
-我们在哪 -男生置物间
- Where are we? - Boys' locker room.
闻起来有股脚臭味
It smells like feet.
这可不是脚臭 好的 来这边
That's not feet. Okay. Come here.
我很害怕
I'm so scared.
想想那些能令你开心的地方
Just go to your happy place.
刚搞破坏的就是能令我开心的地方
We just broke into my happy place.
谁在哪
Who's there?
走 走 跑 跑
Go, go, run, run!
不要这么大声 快跑 快跑
Not so loud! Run! Run!
你怎么样了
So, how you doing?
不好 我很庆幸我的小丑训练课程
Oh, not good. I'm just glad my clown training
让我懂得如何栽跟头
prepared me to take a fall like that.
很好 你以后肯定会对这事喋喋不休
Yeah, and in terms of talking about it,
你是打算说上几周呢 还是几个月呢
Are we looking at weeks, months?
不要小看它造成的伤害
Do not minimize it, you,
你上次穿木屐滑到
who I had to rush to the emergency room
居然要我跑到急诊室看你
that time you fell out of your clogs.
这是你要的柠檬气泡水
There's your bubbly water with lemon.
谢谢你 杰
Thank you, Jay.
你怎么样了
How you doin'?
很难说
Oh, it's hard to tell.
一旦你的腰部
You know, anytime you have
出现了重大损伤
a catastrophic injury to your lumbar area --
你要算有腰一族 那我肯定是水蛇腰了
I could use a little piece of lumbar myself right now.
现在让我的家人当莉莉的监护人
Well, I hope you're comfortable now
你不会有异议了吧
making my family Lily's guardians.
你好 你好
HOLA, HOLA!
你忘了还有歌洛莉亚
You're forgetting about Gloria.
你得承认她和莉莉相处的很不错
Even you have to admit how amazing she is with Lily.
谁家的女儿这么漂亮啊
Mm! Look who's so pretty!
天啊
Oh, my god!
歌洛莉亚 你做了什么
Gloria, what did you do?
我跟你说过了啊
What I told you.
你给她穿了耳洞
You pierced her ears?!
我说过
What I said --
我要用耳环把她点缀得更漂亮
I was going to make her pretty with earrings.
我以为你说的是"发环"
I thought you said "Hair rings."
发环是什么
What are hair rings?
是的 米奇尔 什么是发环
Yes, Mitchell, what are hair rings?
某种能把头发系在后面
Something that you would tie your hair back --
她是这么说的
she said it!
我没有说"发环" 我说的"耳环"
I didn't say "Hair rings." I said "Earrings."
你不喜欢吗
You don't like?
当然不 你带我们的女儿去打洞
Of course not. You punctured our daughter!
但你看两边了吗
But did you see both sides?
除了同志专用耳 我另外一只也打了
I didn't just do the gay ear.
瞧
Look.
天啊
Oh, my god.
Oh, my God.
我觉得咱们逃过一劫了
I actually -- I think we're good.
我们在这里等盖比 好吗
Let's just wait in here for Gabby, okay?
天 我真不敢相信我们刚做了什么
Oh, my god! I can't believe we just did that.
你能相信刚才我们这么做了吗
Can you believe we just did that?
是的 我们玩的很开心 用不着大惊小怪
Yeah, we had a lot of fun. Let's not geek it up.
等等 如果我爱上这种感觉了怎么办
Wait. What if I have a taste for it now?
我会不会开始一直做这种事情
Am I gonna start doing stuff like that all the time?
冷静点 你只不过做了一件坏事
Calm down. You just did one bad thing.
两件
Two.
我还翘掉了今天的大提琴课
I skipped my cello lesson today.
我的老师根本不住那儿
That wasn't even where my teacher lives.
你竟然翘课
You ditched a class?
我-我根本没有时间练习
Well, I-I didn't have time to practice
因为我有曲棍球和辩论小组还有--
Because of lacrosse and debate team and --
你根本不喜欢弹大提琴吧
Do you even like playing the cello?
我喜欢啊
Yeah.
艾丽克斯
Alex?
我讨厌它
I hate it.
那就放弃啊
So quit.
我从没放弃过任何东西
I've never quit anything.
你以前还没闯入过学校呢
You've never broke into a school before.
你不是刚刚也闯了吗
Just did that.
无意冒犯 不过咱们家的希望和梦想
No offense, but the family's hopes and dreams
貌似都寄托在我身上
are kind of pinned on me.
我只是说 就算你没有这么完美
I'm just saying that no one would blame you
也不会有人责怪你的
if you stopped being so perfect.
实际上那样反倒会让我轻松不少
It actually would take a lot of pressure off of me.
我也做过一些坏事
I did something bad, too...
一些没有人知道的事
Something that nobody knows.
-是什么事 -过来
- What? - Come here.
我不能太大声说
I can't say it too loud, okay?
你到底做了什么
What did you do?
菲尔 我只是不确定你是否明白
Phil, I'm just not sure you understand
我会说那些话的原因
why I said what I said.
在我身上有很多你希望能够改变的缺点
There are qualities about me you wish you could change,
但你改不了了 因为我已经定型了
but you can't 'cause I'm all grown up,
可是对卢克来说还不算太晚
but it's not too late for Luke.
好吧
Okay.
亲爱的 卢克身上有无数遗传你的优点
Honey, there are a hundred things about luke
那些都是我绝对喜爱的
that he gets from you that I absolutely love.
只是 只是有这么小小的一部分
It's just this -- this one tiny part
我坚信如果我能探进去 然后改过来
that I'm sure if I could just get in there and just...ee!
克莱尔 他是个很好的孩子
Claire... he's a great kid.
他会没事儿的
He's gonna be fine.
我知道
I know.
我想我应该知道吧
I think I know.
咱们俩在他面前吵架 真是糟透了
I feel terrible that we fought in front of him.
他在回来的路上跟你说什么了吗
Did he say anything about that on the drive here?
我怎么知道 他是跟你回来的
How would I know? He rode with you.
他没跟我回来 他坐的是你的车
He didn't drive with me. He drove with you.
你就承认吧
Just admit it --
除了我的家人 你觉得莉莉被谁养大都行
you want lily raised by anyone but my family.
只是因为那种生活和她了解的一切相去甚远
It's just so far away from everything she knows.
而且那里有位疯狂的阿姨和两头冻奶牛
And then there's the crazy aunts and the frozen cows.
拜托 就在前一小时
Oh, please, in the last hour,
你爸让曼尼在大庭广众之下丢了脸
your father publicly shamed Manny,
把我从半空摔了下来
dropped me from the sky,
他老婆还在我们宝贝的耳朵上打了两个洞
while his wife drilled holes in our baby's head.
所以我才认为
Which is why I think
咱们应该再去克莱尔和菲尔那里看看
we should revisit claire and phil.
我的钥匙呢
Where are my keys?
我们把卢克一个人留在停车场了
We left Luke alone in a parking garage!
我们并不了解整件事
We don't know the whole story.
真的吗
Don't we?
-咱们开谁的车去 -我的
- Whose car are we taking? - Mine.
那我来开车
Then I'm driving!
妈妈
Hey, mom.
-儿子 -卢克
- Buddy! - Luke?
-儿子 -小克
- Buddy! - Lukey?
-太谢谢您了 -宝贝儿 快下来
- Thank you so much. - Honey, get out of there.
谢谢
Thank you!
我很抱歉 我们非常抱歉
I'm so sorry. We are so sorry.
-儿子 你肯定吓坏了吧 -没有
- Oh, buddy, you must've been so scared.- No.
-天哪 -是怎么回事儿
- Oh, god. - Well, what happened?
我知道你们会回来的
Well, I knew you'd come back.
结果你们没来
Then you didn't.
所以我只好去找电话
So I had to go find a phone.
就是那时候我看见了一只迷路的狗
That's when I saw a stray dog
然后和他玩儿了一会儿
and I played with him for a while.
接着我以为我看见我一年级时的老师
Then I thought I saw mrs. Morgan,
摩根太太 她正要进教堂
my first-grade teacher, going into a church.
结果那不是她
It wasn't her,
但是那时教堂正好在举行婚礼
but there was a wedding there.
我就是在那里遇见利特瓦克一家的
That's where I met the Litvaks.
谢谢你们 太感谢了
Oh, thank you! Thank you so much.
恭喜恭喜[Mazel Tov为犹太语的恭喜]
Congratul-- tov.
宝贝儿
Mwah! Oh, baby.
-我能去喝点东西吗 -当然可以
- Can I go get a drink? - Yes, you can.
去喝吧 想喝什么就喝什么
Yes, you can! You can drink whatever you want!
家里有一堆汽水呢
There's tons of soda in there.
多棒的孩子
What an amazing kid!
真不敢相信我会担心他在外边出事
I can't believe I ever worried about him out in the world.
但母亲都这样 对吧 我担心
That's what I do, though, isn't it? I worry.
我担心他 我只不过想到了一点小事
I worry -- I think about a tiny, little thing,
就一直钻牛角尖 直到刚才突然间
and then I obsess on it, until, suddenly,
我脑子里只想着一件事
it's the only thing I can think about.
上帝啊 别让我毁了咱们的儿子
God, please don't let me screw up our son.
你知道他还会因为什么没事吗
You know why else he's gonna be okay?
不知道
No.
因为这个世界上一定还有个担忧的小女生
Because somewhere out there is a worried little girl
像你一样会列一堆清单 会给垃圾分类
who's making lists and labeling bins,
他会找到她的
and he's gonna find her.
小卡
Cam?
我知道你对杰成为莉莉的监护人的事有偏见
I know you're kind of down on jay being lily's guardian.
你不用管这事 曼尼
Now, that's not anything you need to worry about, Manny.
我只是觉得你对他太苛刻了
I just think you're being too hard on him.
我和他在车里小谈了一下
We had a little chat in the car.
很抱歉让你失望了 杰
I'm sorry I let you down, Jay.
我开始觉得如果我连那堵墙都爬不上
I'm starting to think if I couldn't even get up that wall,
-我还奢望去什么露营呢 -别这样说 曼尼
- Then why am I even going on this - Knock it off, Manny.
我们心里都清楚你能做到
We both know you could get up that wall.
你为什么不想去这次旅行
Now, why are you trying to get out of this trip?
我哪有 我兴奋着呢
I'm not. I'm excited to go --
你骗不了我 曼尼
Manny...
好吧
Okay.
我担心洗澡这事儿
I have some concerns about the shower situation.
怎么了
Oh. Because?
-我显然达到了目标体重 -不错啊
- Well, I'm pretty much at my target weight. - That's good.
但是 我没达到我的目标身高
But the thing is, I haven't quite reached my target height.
原来如此
Got it.
首先 你可以不去
All right, first of all, you don't have to go.
我会帮你写张假条
I'll write you a note.
我们周末去做其他有趣的活动
We'll plan on doing something fun this weekend.
-真的吗 -当然
- Really? - You bet.
你不生我的气
And you're not mad at me?
听着 如果你是其他孩子 我就会教训他
Look, if you were a different kid, I'd give you the speech --
害怕是理所当然
You know, "We all have insecurities.
可你必须勇敢面对
You've got to be brave here."
可事实是
But let's face it --
你是我见过最勇敢的孩子
You're already about the bravest kid I know.
-真的吗 -得了吧
- I am? - Come on.
你穿鲜艳的运动夹克去学校 你会吹排箫
You wear blazers to school. You play the pan flute.
你会对女生读情诗
You -- you read poetry to girls.
我在你这年纪的时候 都不敢和女生说话
I couldn't even talk to girls when I was your age.
和这些事迹比起来 洗澡就是小巫见大巫
The shower thing's nothing compared to all that.
无论你如何决定 我永远支持你
So, whatever you decide, I'm behind you.
别 我都设置好了
No, I got that set up just right.
早告诉过你不许碰
I told you about that before.
杰和你这么说的
Jay said that?
他可是十分清醒的
Yeah, and he wasn't drinking or anything.
你准备怎么做
So, what are you gonna do?
我觉得我会去的
I think I'm gonna go.
连鲁本都能不在乎他多余乳头 我还在乎什么
I mean, if Reuben can go with that extra nipple...
我为你自豪 曼尼
I'm proud of you, Manny.
你做的没错
You're doing the right thing, trust me.
你在想什么 歌洛莉亚
I mean, what were you thinking, Gloria?
米奇 我对你说过抱歉了
Ay, Mitch, I said I was sorry.
可我两岁都有耳环了 而且还是大颗的
But I had them since I was 2 -- huge ones.
她这是怎么了
What is she --
是耳环 菲尔
Earrings, Phil. Earrings.
米奇 你想让我成为莉莉的监护人
Mitch, I just wanted to tell you how really touched I was
我备受感动
You'd want me to be lily's guardian.
不用谢 但你出局了
Oh, you're welcome. And you're out.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
我有一个非常重要的声明要说
I have a very important announcement to make.
抱歉 抱歉
Oh. Sorry. Sorry, so rude.
这绝不能原谅 喂
Totally inexcusable. Yello!
米奇尔和我决定 上帝保佑最好没有
Mitchell and I have decided that if, god forbid,
要是我们有什么不测
Anything should happen to us --
-你不用现在就说 -不 我心意已决
- You don't have to do this right now. - No.
我们想让杰和歌洛莉亚成为莉莉的监护人
We would like to Jay and Gloria to be Lily's guardians.
-小卡 -这是正确的决定
- Cam? - It's the right decision.
这真是天大的好消息
That is great news!
莉莉 要是天有不测
Lily, when something horrible happens,
你将会是我的
You're going to be all mine!
那是在"万不得已"的情况下
It really is an "If" Situation.
都是我的
All mine!
我不想破坏现在这美妙的氛围
I don't mean to ruin this really beautiful moment,
可菲尔和我不在名单里吗
But were Phil and I even considered for the position?
克莱尔
Claire?
我们是三个身体健康
I mean, we are the parents
行为得体的孩子的父母
Of three healthy, well-adjusted children who --
亲爱的 我们得去次警察局
Honey, we need to go down to the police station.
我们的女儿们刚因蓄意破坏学校设施被捕
Our daughters just vandalized the school.
这还没完呢
This is not over.
让我们去看你的新房间 莉莉亚娜
Let's go see your new room, Liliana.
那不是她的名字
No, that's not her name.
你怎么回来了
Oh, hey, what are you doing home?
我翘了瑜伽课
Oh, I bailed on yoga.
哦 好吧
Oh, yeah, yeah.
你能去下邮箱那帮我取下
Oh, oh, could you go to the mailbox and get me --
为什么我不能进来
No, why can't I just come in?
-你当然能 我只是 -卡梅隆
- You can. I just - - Cameron?
-怎么了 -看着我
- What? - Look at me.
-我正看着呢 -你做了什么
- I am. - What did you do?
我自己在家待久了无聊
I am home alone for a lot of hours.
你把她弄成香蕉女郎卡门·米兰达
Carmen Miranda?
我只是希望在耳洞愈合前留下纪念
I just wanted a couple before the holes closed up.
卡梅隆
Oh, cameron.
速度帮我和她照一张
All right, just get one with me really quick.
好的 跟爸比来一张
All right. Hey! One for daddy!